Felix Li



fxlisoft@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/fxlisoft



+1 (786) 220-3306



https://fxlisoft.netlify.app

Summary

A seasoned software engineer who loves building web & mobile applications. With 10 years of professional work experience, I am a strong engineering professional with a Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.) focused on Computer Science from Warsaw University of Technology.

I am specialized in building web frontend and mobile applications using React/React-Native and I also love building mobile applications using Kotlin/Swift.

I present myself as a MERN stack developer, so I am a full-stack developer using Javascript.

Years of experience in orchestrating the infrastructure of web and mobile products (including enterprise-level SaaS platforms) on the AWS Cloud.

Experience

Senior Software Developer

Wasobe Inc

Nov 2020 - Present (5 months +)

- Consulted CTO to deliver latest tech stacks and best industry practices.
- Modified React frontend infrastructure to improve performance & resolve potential issues.
- Improved web application rendering performance 10% faster.

Senior Mobile Developer

Ecosys Technology

Jan 2020 - Nov 2020 (11 months)

- Designed and released the minimum viable product, closely collaborating with the backend team.
- Built React-Native mobile application with camera / photo editing tools integrated.
- 100% client satisfaction and released the product for in-company use.

Texterial Senior Web Developer

Textual

Mar 2019 - Nov 2019 (9 months)

- Modernized the innovative e-commerce platform by leading the frontend development team as a principle developer.
- Committed to SaaS platform development and maintenance project as a web developer.
- Delivered 100% functional SaaS platform to several companies and successfully signed contracts.



Senior Web Developer

SESH, inc

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019 (7 months)

- Managed a team of 5 web developers to deliver web frontend / backend. Organized and launched the entire development process, supervised day-to-day progress of development works of team members.

- Built React web frontend & Node backend, hosted on AWS cloud. Developed live streaming & recording platform using wowza, customized Jitsi frontend, created WebRTC server in Node.
- Delivered platform to the client successfully in agreed timeline and acquired 100% client satisfaction.

Senior Mobile Developer

Wiredcraft

Aug 2017 - Jul 2018 (1 year)

- Built complex animations using OpenGL and animation libraries to deliver the best user interface and user experiences of Starbucks mobile applications.
- Modified animation modules to make animations realistic and improved applications' performance 20% faster as a principal mobile developer.
- Accomplished animation implementation goals and delivered product in time.

Senior Mobile Developer

Stitch Health

Nov 2015 - Jul 2017 (1 year 9 months)

- Managed a team of 3 developers, organized and launched the mobile application development process.
- Built infrastructure of chatting platform using RocketChat & Socket.io as a mobile team lead.
- Successfully published the product to Apple and Google play store.

Full Stack Developer

Art Saint Louis

Jun 2013 - Nov 2015 (2 years 6 months)

- Organized and launched the entire development process, committed to Art selling platform development and maintenance project as a solo developer.
- Built iOS & Android mobile applications as well as .Net backend.
- Successfully published the platform to the online market place.

Education

Warsaw University of Technology

Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.), Computer Science 2009 - 2010

Software Engineering | Cloud Computation | Project Management

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Programming

2005 - 2009

Data Structure & Algorithm | Computer Programming

Skills

React.js • React Native • Node.js • GraphQL • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Firebase • Android Development • iOS Development • Vue.js • Webrtc